# Sam McLeod

Ops Lead, Linux Engineer, DevOps Platform Delivery Specialist

smj@fastmail.com

# Summary

Note: I haven't updated my profile in 3-4 years, I should probably do this at some point.

If you asked six DevOps engineers to define their jobs, you would get seven different answers... A devops engineer sometimes needs to be a business-process consultant, corporate visionary, janitor, software engineer, electrical engineer, economist, psychiatrist, mind reader, and, occasionally a bartender.

"Easy things should be easy, and hard things should be possible."

- Larry Wall

# Experience

## Operations Lead / Senior DevOps Engineer at Infoxchange Australia

October 2012 - Present (3 years 9 months)

Leading a team of systems engineers in architecting, deploying, managing, optimising and automating an environment of approximately 300 servers and over 300 application / container instances.

Involved daily with technologies such as Puppet, Docker, Nagios, ElasticSearch, RabbitMQ, Logstash, Docker, XenServer, Nginx, Git, GitLab Enterprise, PostgreSQL, Blade, Flash Storage & Cloud Technology & serving the organisation as a trusted technical advisor.

- -DevOps Coordination
- -Product Delivery Engineering & Performance Analysis
- -Team Leadership / Management
- -Systems Architecture
- -SAN Design & Architecture
- -Systems Engineering
- -Virtualisation Architecture & Engineering
- -Database Administration & Performance Engineering
- -Systems Automation
- -Continuous Integration & Delivery Systems
- -Security Auditing & Automation
- -Tender Response & Delivery

#### Unix / Linux Administrator at Sensis

April 2012 - October 2012 (7 months)

#### Unix / Linux Administrator at Telstra

April 2012 - October 2012 (7 months)

Working for Sensis (Part of Telstra) I was part of a team of skilled Linux/Unix engineers responsible for maintaining, deploying and improving a large scale environment working with systems such as Nagios, Puppet, VMware, Redhat, Solaris and AIX as well as all the standard day-to-day tools that are part of a System Administrator's tool belt.

My role included working reactively on incidents as they occur, internal improvement projects, application deployments both in and out-of-hours.

#### Linux / Unix Systems Administrator at Canterbury District Health Board

January 2008 - March 2012 (4 years 3 months)

System Administrator for various Red Hat, AIX, Microsoft servers.

Primary systems:

- -Main patient management system for the greater South Island. (Solaris)
- -Canterbury Health Laboratories Delphic Servers. (AIX)
- -Various other Redhat Servers.

Co-administrator for 25-30 Unix/Linux servers.

Various work with Windows Server 2003 / 2008.

#### Managing Director at Dealsafe Ltd.

July 2010 - August 2011 (1 year 2 months)

Web Directory Startup

#### **Director / Technician at Second Generation Computing**

January 2000 - January 2010 (10 years 1 month)

Self-employed part time company setting up small business networks, servers and provided troubleshooting and technical assistance / repairs.

#### **Engineer at Doortech Ltd.**

January 2006 - January 2008 (2 years 1 month)

Worked with hydro / mechanical & electronic door and security systems.

# Volunteer Experience

## Co-founder, Event Organiser, Graphic Design and Protester at ACC Public Equality Group

January 2011 - January 2012

## Organizations

#### **Infrastructure Coders Melbourne**

Speaker & Attendee

October 2012 to Present

#### **Melbourne Search Group**

Speaker & Attendee

June 2014 to Present

http://ixa.io/2014/06/05/search-a-journey-of-delivery-on-a-budget/

#### The Royal Society Of New Zealand

Member

January 2010 to April 2012

#### **DevOps Melbourne**

Speaker & Attendee

2014 to Present

## Certifications

## **Redhat Certified Engineer (RCHE)**

Auldhouse Training / Red Hat License 111-171-302

## **Certified Associate in Project Management (CAPM)**

PMI

#### A+, Network+, Linux+, Systems Security Design

Computer Power Institute

#### **CCNA**

Computer Power Institute

### **Advanced Customer Management Training**

Computer Power Institute

#### **ITIL Foundations**

Microsoft

# Skills & Expertise

### **High Availability Clustering**

**Linux System Administration** 

Linux

**Product Delivery** 

**ElasticSearch** 

**Team Leadership** 

**Storage Area Networks** 

**Solaris** 

Debian Virtualization PostgreSQL Servers

Nagios Incident Management

Xen

**RedHat** 

**System Administration** 

**Red Hat Linux** 

Unix

**Windows Server** 

Ubuntu

**Shell Scripting** 

**RHEL** 

Samba

**SSH** 

**Puppet** 

Mac OS X

**Unix Shell Scripting** 

**DRBD** 

**Bash** 

**Troubleshooting** 

**AIX** 

**Open Source** 

ITIL

**RHCE** 

**Linux Server** 

**DevOps** 

Windows

**PMP** 

**Active Directory** 

Wireshark

**Unix Administration** 

Linux server administration

Logstash

RabbitMQ

**Certified Associate in Project Management (CAPM)** 

**CAPM** 

**HP Storageworks** 

XenServer

**Continuous Integration** 

Education

Redhat

Redhat Certified Systems Administrator, IT Engineering, 2012 - 2012

Grade: A+

**Auldhouse Training Ltd.** 

RHCSA, Information Technology, 2011 - 2011

Activities and Societies: Red Hat Certified System Administrator

**Computer Power Institute** 

Diploma Of Network Engineering, Information Technology, 2008 - 2010

**Christchurch College of Computing** 

Programming Introduction, Information Technology, 2004 - 2004

Infracoders Infracoders

#### Interests

Linux / Unix Administration & Engineering

DevOps Culture Change

Organisational Efficiency

**Product Delivery** 

HiFi / Audio Gear

Music Collecting

Motorbiking

#### Courses

## **Independent Coursework**

Ruby on Rails Introduction Course

Johns Hopkins University

Puppet Fundamentals Puppetlabs

Decision Quality Stanford University

# Sam McLeod

Ops Lead, Linux Engineer, DevOps Platform Delivery Specialist

smj@fastmail.com



## 7 people have recommended Sam

"Sam is a leader in DevOps and has a unique combination of technical and soft skills. Through being passionate about emerging technology while having experience in creating stable, reliable complex systems he can see new and creative solutions to problems while also gaining buy in for large changes to be supported throughout organisations. Sam lives to make our lives better through technology, he is very active in Melbourne meetup / DevOps communities, conferences, and is always sharing interesting technological finds with coworkers. I look to Sam for both technology review and professional advice."

— Brett Rann, Senior Software Developer, Infoxchange, worked indirectly for Sam at Infoxchange Australia

"Ah, Sam -- the one comrade I have met via Twitter regarding the nature of our fields. I am certainly very, very picky in my recommendations but while, I "The Expert" work, I find myself bending to the absolute technical solitude that is Sam. He is the promoter of my craft as well as the deconstruction of ideas I had per our field. If you need one reason to back Sam, it is simply that he strives for solutions, contributes to such solutions, and is a universal genius! "

— **Jesse Benedict**, *Senior Engineer*, *Citrix*, was with another company when working with Sam at Infoxchange Australia

"Sam is a real driver for change and innovation. He's passionate about squeezing the most out of everything he's given, and does an excellent job of it. Since working with Sam, he's been a taken a leading role in the complete overhaul of Infoxchange's operations team, environments and processes that have resulted in significant improvements across the board in stability, performance and developer satisfaction."

- Ricky Cook, worked directly with Sam at Infoxchange Australia

"Sam is a very open hearted and highly skilled person, who not only has a lot of knowledge but is capable of providing this to other team members in a way that a single explanation leaves no open questions. He can solve difficult situations keeping his calm and not losing focus on the issue no matter how much pressure lays upon him. It has been a fantastic experience and honour for me to work with Sam and I would highly recommend him for any Unix related job and hope that I can work again with him in future."

— **David Willis**, worked directly with Sam at Sensis

"Sam was/is a geat Unix admin person and wiiling to hep out and best of all learn!"

### — Jules Ambrosi, worked with Sam at Telstra

"Sam is always keen to assist with problem solving and assisting whenever it is required. He has demonstrated good technical skills and shows great initiative. Works very well with others and is always friendly and approachable."

### — John Moodie, worked directly with Sam at Canterbury District Health Board

"Sam has great technical skills and is very customer focused. He is able to work within a team environment and builds excelent relationships with his customers and clients."

— Paul Goddard, managed Sam indirectly at Canterbury District Health Board

Contact Sam on LinkedIn